SIOBHAN BAINES

17 Woodlea Grove, Yeadon, Leeds, LS19 7YT
Telephone: 07766740070
Email: baines.smb@gmail.com
LinkedIn: Siobhan Baines

PROFILE

Accomplished IT Lead equipped with 30 years' experience in delivering a variety of solutions on the IBM AS400 platform, including knowledge transfer, project management, change management and requirements gathering as well as providing exceptional troubleshooting and problem-solving skills and the highest standard of customer service. Demonstrates high levels of business acumen, understands business demands and manages day-to-day service operations of applications, ensuring the smooth handling of incidents and requests across a wide range of software, services and systems. International collaborator, who builds strong, productive, working relationships across Europe, Japan and Australia. Consummate leader, who builds, coaches and directs high performing support teams and manages the allocation of resources to projects. Now seeking new challenges where core transferable expertise and skills can be applied to business change, enhancing operational performance and growing revenue.

TRANSFERABLE EXPERTISE

Leadership: Self-reliant, strong critical decision making, motivating, team building, delegating and monitoring quality

Project Management: Recognised for appropriate workflow management to ensure all work is prioritised and executed to meet client needs

Stakeholder Management: Forming, monitoring and maintaining constructive relationships by influencing stakeholders' expectations at all organisation levels, understanding their needs and delivering against agreed timescales

Analysis: Ability to identify systemic opportunities and implement detailed strategies to support effective transformative change. Implement set of practices and processes that lead to development of a set of well-formed business requirements from which the business solutions can be developed

Requirements Gathering: Expertise in utilising a variety of investigative techniques to elicit information from stakeholders and develop ways to manage their interests and expectations

Continuous Improvement: Proven ability to identify areas for further development, and able to support others in the process. Has an analytical and problem-solving approach to work. Excels at prioritising flexibly to meet rapidly changing needs. Adept at crisis and risk management

Technical Skills: Packages: JDE World 7.3 & 9.4 (including AR, AP, GL, SOX, PO, SO), Data3

Programming Languages: RPGIII, RPGIV, RPGLE, CL, CLLE, AS400 query language

Applications: Create!Print, Bartender, Aldon, BizAgi, BRMS, MQ, IIB, Transform, Robot Scheduler, Showcase Query,

Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Visio)

KEY SKILLS

- Developer in RPG on IBM AS400
- Critical thinking
- Process modelling/As-is and To-be
- Business Analysis toolkit
- Risk management
- Structured analysis and design

- Change Management
- Business Transformation
- Applications Support
- Knowledge Transfer
- Cross-functional collaboration
- Data Management and Reporting

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Mar 2020 - Present

Freelance Business Analyst - Baines SM Ltd

Collaborate a variety of 3rd Party and internal, local and international stakeholders to enable successful implementation of new outsourced financial systems and produce BS documentation

Oct 2019 – Jan 2020 **Technology Lead** - Infosys

- Provide Application Support, identify and analyse core requirements and key features of projects as well as business and technical knowledge transfer
- Liaise with clients for project briefing, consultation, installation and closeout reviews
- Supervise activities between internal and external resources, and facilitate smooth workflow for service delivery

JDE World Systems Analyst - Hallmark Cards

An international subsidiary of privately owned Hallmark Cards in Kansas City in the greetings industry, employs 1,310 with a turnover of £142m pa. Major UK customers include Marks & Spencer, Tesco, Waitrose and Morrisons.

Positions Held:

2016 - 2019

Business Analyst / Senior JDE Support Technician

- Collaborated with a variety of internal stakeholders to provide on-site support for the Japan office systems upgrade
- Served as Consultant across financial reporting, acted as liaison for Australian and Central Europe system upgrades
- Delivered complex knowledge transfer sessions to Infosys across multiple process areas, to facilitate their take-on of services
- IBM MQ and IIB administration including dealing with external suppliers
- Supported the delivery of a new Pay-On-Scan process, modified a self-bill process to meet changing business requirements for major customers including Marks & Spencer and Morrisons. Held responsibility for the role-based security module and purchase order approvals process
- Simultaneously supported JDE World legacy 7.3 and current 9.4 systems, IBM MQ and IIB, and Robot Scheduler
- End-to-end management for the development deployment through Aldon LMi

2012 - 2016

IT Finance Stream Lead and Application Support Analyst

- Pivotal member in the Hallmark strategic business transformation project which de-risked the legacy core system JDE World 7.3 to upgrade to vanilla JDE World 9.3.1
- Gained insights into the needs of the business by undertaking requirements gathering, As-Is and To-Be process
 flows, business specifications, technical specifications, system testing, 'hand-holding' testers throughout UAT, golive data transfers and post go-live support
- Played a key role in the configuration of a self-bill invoicing and reconciliation model for the Marks & Spencer
 account, utilised expertise to provide technical guidance across the financial module, assisted in configuring the
 new to 9.3 role-based security module, supporting legacy JDE 7.3 systems and managing multiple IBM AS400
 systems operation tasks including the BRMS backup system

2006 - 2011

Analyst Programmer

- Enhanced efficiency by liaising with the business, to gain an understanding of their needs; utilised influencing skills within meetings to set acceptable archiving criteria to reduce the amount of unnecessary data in JDE.
- Expanded the Ship Confirmation suite of programs to interface with SAP EWM; supported users by producing a technical user guide and created various labels in an antiquated BarTender system
- Liaised with many business stakeholders, developed and implemented a data archiving suite including a mechanism for data retrieval
- Developed and embedded interfaces to the Savoye LM7 warehousing system including the business-critical Ship Confirmation suite of programs
- Managed numerous projects including a project to increase the expiry year within JDE to ensure bespoke changes were compatible. Monitored all project deliverables including timing, scope and budgets to mitigate any risks

Key Achievements:

- Successfully represented colleagues through TUPE and redundancy processes
- On-site Japanese go-live hyper-care support, JDE security and PO approval design
- First point of contact IBM MQ, IIB, Robot, Aldon, Showcase and role-based security when the department was downsized

Additional Employment History

Jan 2005 - Dec 2006

Jul 2002 - Jan 2005

May 1990 - Jul 2002

Oct 1989 - Apr 1990

Sept 1987 - Sept 1989

Ist/2nd Line Support and Development Analysis Programmer - Jacuzzi UK

Analyst Programmer - William Hill Organization

Company Secretary and Contract Analyst Programmer - Hapwell Ltd

Analyst Programmer - Higham's Computer Services Ltd

Trainee Programmer/Analyst Programmer - Baxter Healthcare Ltd

QUALIFICATIONS

Professional

ITIL Foundation Certified RPG 4 crossover & ILE Broker Administration

Personal

BSc (Hons) Open Strategy, Collaboration and Finance Professional Certificate in Accounting Diploma of Higher Education Open University Introduction to Java and WebSphere IDE Introduction to and Advanced RPG

Certificate in Business Studies AAT Level 2 Certificate for Accounting Technicians 2 A' levels and 8 O' levels inc Mathematics and English